heartofthe.net 2012-09-20

# Privacy | HeartOfThe.Net - Create your free blog

HeartOfThe.Net takes the private nature of your personal information very seriously. This Privacy Policy (which we adapted from a policy originally provided by [Automattic](http://www.automattic.com/) ([WordPress.com](http://www.wordpress.com/))) describes how we treat the information we collect when you visit and use the website available at HeartOfThe.Net (the “Website”) and is made available under the **Creative Commons Sharealike** license. Please read this notice very carefully.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, HeartOfThe.Net collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. HeartOfThe.Net’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how HeartOfThe.Net’s visitors use its Website. From time to time, HeartOfThe.Net may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its Website.

HeartOfThe.Net also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. HeartOfThe.Net does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below. 

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to the Website choose to interact with HeartOfThe.Net in ways that require HeartOfThe.Net to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that HeartOfThe.Net gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a blog at HeartOfThe.Net to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with HeartOfThe.Net are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, HeartOfThe.Net collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with HeartOfThe.Net. HeartOfThe.Net does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

HeartOfThe.Net does not collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If you believe that a child has provided HeartOfThe.Net with personally identifiable information without the consent of his or her parent or guardian, please contact us at [support@heartofthe.net](mailto:support@heartofthe.net). If HeartOfThe.Net becomes aware that a child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete such information.

## Aggregated Statistics

HeartOfThe.Net may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to the Website. For instance, HeartOfThe.Net may monitor the most popular blogs on the HeartOfThe.Net site to help identify spam. HeartOfThe.Net may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, HeartOfThe.Net does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

## Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

HeartOfThe.Net discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on HeartOfThe.Net’s behalf or to provide services available at the Website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using the Website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. In addition, in some cases we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if HeartOfThe.Net or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that HeartOfThe.Net goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquiror of HeartOfThe.Net may continue to use your personal and non-personal information only as set forth in this policy. Otherwise, HeartOfThe.Net will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations or as described above, HeartOfThe.Net discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when HeartOfThe.Net believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of HeartOfThe.Net, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of the HeartOfThe.Net Website and have supplied your email address, HeartOfThe.Net may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with HeartOfThe.Net and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. HeartOfThe.Net takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

You should also be aware that if you submit information to “chat rooms,” “forums” or “message boards” such information becomes public information, meaning that you lose any privacy rights you might have with regards to that information. Such disclosures may also increase your chances of receiving unwanted communications.

For users outside the United States, please note that any personally-identifiable information you enter into the Website will be transferred out of your country and into the United States. You consent to such transfer through your use of the Website. You also warrant that you have the right to transfer such information outside your country and into the United States.

## Links to Third Party Sites

This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by HeartOfThe.Net. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that HeartOfThe.Net does not own or control, or employees that HeartOfThe.Net does not manage. The Website contains links to third party websites. Any information you provide to, or that is collected by, third-party sites may be subject to the privacy policies of those sites, if any. We encourage you to read such privacy policies of any third-party sites you visit. It is the sole responsibility of such third parties to adhere to any applicable restrictions on the disclosure of your personally-identifying information, and HeartOfThe.Net and its affiliates shall not be liable for wrongful use or disclosure of your personally-identifying information by any third party.

## Security

All non-personally-identifying information, potentially personally-identifying and personally identifying-information described above is stored on restricted database servers.

## Choice/Opt-out

If we ever send you information by e-mail concerning new products, services or information that you did not expressly request, we will provide you with an e-mail address by which you may request no further notices.

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. HeartOfThe.Net uses cookies to help HeartOfThe.Net identify and track visitors, their usage of the HeartOfThe.Net Website, and their Website access preferences. HeartOfThe.Net visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the HeartOfThe.Net Website, with the drawback that certain features of HeartOfThe.Net’s Website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

## Address Book Data

Any external address book data (email contacts, etc.) that a user voluntarily gives HeartOfThe.Net access to will only be used for the described feature (looking up friends, etc.), and will not be stored or repurposed.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, HeartOfThe.Net may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in HeartOfThe.Net’s sole discretion. If we do then we’ll notify you by posting the amended policy on the Website or by emailing you of the nature of the modifications along with a link to the modified document so that you can review it. In all cases, use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.

## Review and Access

Upon your request, we will provide you with a summary of the information we collect about you. You will have the opportunity to correct, update, modify or delete this information by sending an e-mail to [support@heartofthe.net](mailto:support@heartofthe.net). Please note that some information may remain in our records after deletion of your account.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this policy or our site in general, please contact us at [support@heartofthe.net](mailto:support@heartofthe.net).
